Richard Barton

https://rickb.org/resume (Last updated: 2024/10/21)

Professional Summary

I describe myself as a Product Engineer or Product Developer. My concern is with how to help the vision of the product team get into the hands of the end users. The path I have found to be very good at helping turn the business vision into user's value is by following the agile manifesto's 12 principles. The 12 principles offer the guidance, but the specifics can vary a lot depending on how the team chooses to do the implementations. I care a great deal about providing good user experiences and fulfilling the business's vision, however there must be a balance struck between that and making sure the tech debt is paid off too.

Education

- Master of Science in Information Systems | University of Missouri St. Louis | Graduated: Dec. 2011
- Bachelor of Arts in Psychology | University of Missouri St. Louis | Graduated: May. 2005

Skills

All things Web (and some that aren't (3))

Professional Experiences

- Eastman Chemical Company (St. Louis, MO) Mar. 2022 to Present | Senior Software Architect
 - An innovative specialty materials company that makes a material difference in people's lives.
- Eastman Chemical Company (St. Louis, MO) Mar. 2020 to Present | Full Stack Web Developer
 - o An innovative specialty materials company that makes a material difference in people's lives.
- Hunter Engineering Company (St. Louis, MO) Aug. 2019 to Mar. 2020 | Lead Angular Developer
 - Over 350 patented inventions from the largest wheel service product development staff in the world.
 Hunter's award-winning team of more than 75 engineers and support staff is unequalled in the industry.
- Intercard (St. Louis, MO) Nov. 2018 to Aug. 2019 | Senior Software Engineer
 - Offer innovative solutions allow us to maintain the leadership position in cash management and marketing systems around the world.
- Maritz (St. Louis, MO) Apr. 2015 to Nov. 2018 | App Developer
 - Maritz Travel, a Maritz Global Events company, works with meeting planners, sales operations and procurement teams to deliver business meetings and incentive travel programs for corporate, Fortune 100 companies. We help our clients create exceptional experiences through innovative design, flawless execution, leading-edge technology solutions, and our extensive partner network throughout North America and across the globe.
- FleishmanHillard (St. Louis, MO) Dec. 2011 to Apr. 2015 | Web Developer
 - FleishmanHillard is an international communications company. The intranet is built on SharePoint. There are many legacy .NET applications that live in SharePoint but are not SP solutions. There are many legacy SharePoint applications. I support that environment and help the other MIS departments with their needs as well. Since early-2014 my team's focus has been on data visualization and fast and fluid HTML5 websites.

- Sextant Technology Partners (St. Louis, MO) Nov. 2010 to Dec. 2011 | Network Engineer
 - Sextant Technology Partners was a small IT consultant company whose main clients consisted of law firms in the St. Louis region. Sextant specialized in document management and backups but they provided full service to any client depending on needs.